We are going to be
looking into the word this morning.
I know that it is 2020. How many of you
have New Year's resolutions? Let me see
your hands.
[cough]
[clears throat]
Very good. Now, how many of you have New
Year's resolutions that you plan to
keep? Let me see your hands.
You know how those New Year's
resolutions
can be.
But today I want to speak to you about
one [clears throat] New Year resolution
that I think is crucial.
And that New Year resolution is really
to be a better Christian. Amen.
Amen.
So [clears throat] I'm going to invite
you to pray with me as we open the word
of God
and
listen to what he has to say to us
today. Let's pray. Heavenly Father,
[clears throat] Lord, I ask that you
would just speak to your people today.
Lord, you know that I have uh issues
with my throat right now. Um,
and I just pray that you would just uh
help me to speak
uh despite
uh myself.
This we pray in the precious name of
Jesus. Let everyone say amen.
I want to invite you to turn in your
Bibles to the book of Daniel chapter 1.
[clears throat]
Daniel
chapter 1.
I want to read to you verse I actually
have my water right here. So thank you.
um water with oil of oregano.
One time I made the mistake of
announcing that I was uh sick from the
pulp and I was preaching someplace else
and I think I had like 10 people come up
on the platform to give me stuff
for my and it was all being recorded. Um
but thank you, thank you, thank you. I'm
going to drink this water. Remind me to
drink my water as I'm up here preaching.
Okay. Daniel chapter 1 beginning with
verse one. The Bible says,
"In the third year of the reign of
Jehookim, king of Judah, came
Nebuchadnezzar,
king of Babylon, unto Jerusalem and
besieged it.
And the Lord gave Jehoakim, king of
Judah, into his hand, with, if you can
read this part with me, everyone, part
of
the vessels of the house of God, which
he carried into the land of Shinar, to
the house of his God.
And he brought the vessels into the
house into the treasure house of his
God. Let me pause for a moment.
[clears throat]
And here we have Nebuchadnezzar. The
Bible describes Nebuchadnezzar, king of
Babylon, as besieging Jerusalem, and
taking part of the vessels of the house
of God, meaning the sanctuary. And where
did he take it to?
He took it to his house, the house of
his gods in Babylon.
I want to invite you to turn again with
me to the book of 2 Chronicles, chapter
36.
We're going to look at verses 9 and 10.
2 Chronicles
36:es
9 and 10. It's up on the screen.
The Bible says, "Jhoin was 8 years old
when he began to reign, [clears throat]
and he reigned 3 months and 10 days in
Jerusalem, and he did that which was
evil in the sight of the Lord." Verse
10.
And when the year was expired, King
Nebuchadnezzar sent and brought him to
Babylon with, read that with me,
everyone, the goodly what? Vessels
[clears throat] of the house of the Lord
and made Zedekiah his brother king over
Judah and Jerusalem. Now, you're not
reading the same story here. You're
actually reading that there were two
times that Nebuchadnezzar went to
Jerusalem so far. Um, and attacked the
city and took vessels out of where?
Out of the house of God and did what?
Brought it to Babylon.
Now, I want you to notice with me, same
chapter, verse 11.
Zedekiah was 120 years old when he began
to reign. And he reigned 11 years in
Jerusalem. And he did that which was
what? Evil in the sight of the Lord his
God, and humbled not himself before
Jeremiah the prophet, speaking from the
mouth of the Lord.
[clears throat] And he also rebelled
against King Nebuchadnezzar, who made
him swear by God, but he stiffened his
neck and hardened his heart from turning
unto the Isra unto the Lord God of
Israel.
Moreover, all the chief priests, chief
of the priests, and the people
transgressed very much after all the
watts, abominations [clears throat]
of the heathen, and polluted the house
of the Lord, which he had hallowed in
Jerusalem.
[laughter] And the Lord God of their
fathers sent to them
by his messengers rising up at times and
sending because he had compassion on his
people and on his dwelling place.
But they mocked the messengers of God
[clears throat]
and despised his words and misused his
prophets until the wrath of the Lord
rose against his people till there was
no remedy. Verse 17.
Therefore he brought on them the king
account of the cales who slew their
young men with the sword in the house of
their sanctuary
and had no compassion upon young man or
maiden
old man or him that stooped for age. He
gave them all into his hands. Verse 18.
and all the read that with me everyone
vessels of the house of God great and
small and the treasures of the house of
the Lord and the treasures of the king
and of his princes. All these he brought
to Babylon. Verse 19. And they burnt the
house of God and break down the wall of
Jerusalem
and burnt all the palaces thereof with
fire and destroyed all the goodly
vessels thereof.
How many times did Nebuchadnezzar go to
Babylon and attack it?
How many times?
Three times.
And each time, what did he do?
He took some of the vessels of the house
of God and did what? Brought it to
Babylon.
Brought it to where, everyone?
Brought it to Babylon.
It's significant that it was little by
little that the treasures of the house
of God, the treasures of the sanctuary
were brought to Babylon and held there
in the house of Nebuchadnezzar's God.
So why did God allow this? What do you
think?
Why did God allow
the treasures of his house
of the sanctuary
to be taken like this?
Help me out. What do you think?
Teach them a lesson.
To teach them a lesson. Why did they
need a lesson?
Because they they were rebelling. Pretty
simple answer. The children of Israel
were rebelling against God. And as a
result,
Babylon comes and takes the treasures of
the house of God little by little into
their own country.
I [clears throat] want you to notice
with me Ezekiel chapter 8. In Ezekiel
8:es 5 and 6, the Bible tells us exactly
why this happens.
Ezekiel is in vision. The Bible says,
"Then he said unto me, son of man, lift
up thine eyes now the way toward the
north. So I lifted up my eyes the way
toward the north, and behold, northward
of the gate of the altar, this image of
jealousy in the entry." Verse six, he
said unto me," Son of man, seeest thou
what they do, even the great
abominations that the house of Israel
committeth there,
that I should do what?
Go far off from my sanctuary, but turn
thee yet again, and thou shalt see
greater abominations." What was Israel
doing?
Why did God leave his sanctuary?
Because of
the abominations
that were happening in the temple.
And as a result of those abominations,
God allows another nation to come
and capture
the temple.
So, what were these abominations?
I want to invite you again to turn with
me to the book of Proverbs, chapter 6,
16.
Proverbs, chapter 6, 16. And I want you
to notice this very carefully with me.
[cough and clears throat]
The Bible says here, "These six things
does the Lord hate. Yay, seven are an
what? an abomination unto him.
What are those seven things that are an
abomination unto him? Let's find out.
Verse 17,
a proud what?
A proud
look. Let me ask you a question. How
many of you have ever thought that a
proud look was an abomination unto God?
Like when we think about things that are
abomination unto God. This morning we
were talking in Sabbath school and you
know we were mentioning a couple of
things that we that people thought were
abominations unto God. But many people
don't realize that one of the things
that God specifically calls an
abomination
is a proud look.
What else?
A lying what?
A lying tongue.
A lying tongue to God is an abomination.
What else? Hands that shed innocent
blood.
Let's look at verse 18. A heart that
what?
Deiseth mis wicked wicked imaginations
and feet that be what? Swift and running
to mischief. Now pause for a second. I
want you to see if you notice a common
thread in these two verses that I just
read.
Did you notice a common thread about the
things that are an abomination unto the
Lord?
I want you to think it. Can we go back
to verse 17?
And and I'm going to see if I can help
you here without helping you too much.
A proud what?
Look, a lying what?
Tongue.
And
what?
Hands that shed innocent blood. Let's go
to the next verse. Uh, a what?
Okay, pause for a second. Do any of you
see a common thread in these two verses?
The body.
In other words, eyes, hands,
feet,
heart, right? We're talking about a
person.
[clears throat]
Tongue. We're talking now. Now,
how many of you realize
that in the book of 1 Corinthians
chapter 3, we don't need to turn there
right now, but 1 Corinthians chapter 3,
the Bible says, "Know ye not that you
are what?
The temple of God." So, if we have any
temples in here, give me just raise your
hand. I'm a temple. I'm a temple. I'm a
temple. Now, why did God allow the items
of the temple to be taken into
captivity? Because of
the abominations being done where?
In the temple. Because of the
abominations being done in the temple,
the temple was ultimately taken captive
by Babylon.
Are you with me so far?
So, so now we look at these what what is
an abomination unto God? And we see, wo,
a heart that devises wickedness, a lying
tongue, hands that shed blood, feet that
are swift to uh to mischief. In other
words, God is pointing out here that
that
the temple, the person that does these
things is in actuality
committing abominations where
in the temple.
Let me keep reading. Verse 19.
a false witness that
speaks what? Lies. And he that sweth
what? Discord among brethren. These are
the things that are an abomination unto
God.
And as we look back at ancient Israel
and we think, man, wow, they they they
How many of you look back at Israel and
go, man, those were a stubborn people?
They were rebellious.
If I were in those days, surely
I would have been able to identify that
rebellion and I would have been one that
really stood for God. Amen.
Beloved, all we have to do is look at
this list of abominations
and realize something very important. I
want to go to 1 Corinthians chapter
3:16. I want you to notice this. 1
Corinthians 3:16. Know you not that you
are what?
The temple of God and that the spirit of
God dwells in you. And now notice this
next verse. If any man do what?
If any man what?
Defile the temple. Now pause for a
second.
What is it that defiles the temple? What
does God say defiles the temple? He
calls it a word. That word is what?
Abominations.
So you mean that if I have a proud look
or a lying tongue or hands that are hu
that that shed blood or feet that are
swift to mischief, you mean to tell me
that I am actually
defiling
my temple. Is that true?
Yeah. So God says, "If any man defile
the temple of God, him shall God what?
Destroy. For the temple of God is holy.
which temple you are.
But beloved, I want you to catch
something here.
[clears throat]
You see, your temple is not destroyed
all at one time.
Do you catch what I just said?
Remember, Nebuchadnezzar took away parts
of the temple. How?
Little by little,
it was because of the compromises and
because of the the the constant
rebellion against God that little by
little, the articles of furniture in the
sanctuary end up where?
In Babylon.
God said in Exodus 25:8,
"Let them make me a sanctuary that I may
do what?"
Dwell among them. Why did he say that?
Why was why did he say let them make me
a sanctuary that I may dwell among them?
What is the purpose of the sanctuary?
Okay, to worship God. But but I would
suggest that there is there is an even
greater and more urgent purpose to the
sanctuary.
What what was a sanctuary given to teach
man?
The plan of salvation which involves
the cleansing
from sins.
Amen.
The sanctuary was given to teach man how
he could dwell with God. But listen
carefully. Why could man not dwell with
God?
Because of what? Sin. Isaiah 59:2.
Notice what it says. Isaiah 59:2. But
your what? Iniquities have separated
between you and your God, and your sins
have hid his face from you that he will
not hear. So if sin causes separation
from God, then God said, "Let them make
me a sanctuary that I may dwell among
them." signifying that the sanctuary was
the way in which God the the method by
where God would cause it so that he
could dwell with man. Does that make
sense?
So So the sanctuary
was God's way of connecting with us,
removing sin out of the way so that he
could connect with us. So can someone
tell me what is sin?
Sin is transgression of the law. And
where do we transgress the law?
That's you. You transgress the law where
[clears throat]
in your temples.
You transgress the law in your mind.
So the sanctuary was designed to lead us
away from transgressing the law. where
in our minds because if you don't do it
in your mind then your hands won't do it
either.
Did you catch what I just said? You see,
your mind is what controls your feet.
Your mind is what controls your hands.
Your mind is what controls your tongue.
So God gave us a sanctuary in essence to
teach us how to control
your mind.
I need you to follow this
different principles. Yes.
So, I want you to help me out here. Like
the altar of sacrifice. What principle
do you think that represented?
The death of Jesus. Okay, very good.
What how would you describe? What are
some things you would use to describe
principles that would point to the death
of Christ?
Humility. Who said that? Who? Okay,
you're being humble. Okay, there you go.
Humility.
Humility. So, so let me ask you, is that
a principle that you think God would
like his people to exhibit in the mind?
Yeah. Listen carefully.
Each article of furniture represents a
principle
which God wants us to exhibit
in the mind.
So the altar of sacrifice representing
humility. Christ humbled himself and
became obedient unto death even the
death of the cross. God is saying listen
when you look at the sanctuary I want
you to understand the principle of
humility and I want you to exercise
that. Why? Because humility
is something that will keep you away
from abominations.
Wait, what was the first abomination?
Oh,
a proud look. So God is saying if you
exercise the principle of the altar of
sacrifice, that will keep you from
having what?
a proud look.
And this is what God is trying to do.
He's trying to show us that the articles
of furniture all represent principles
that we ought to be exercising where?
In the mind. But there's a problem.
Because you see, we have an adversary by
the name of Satan
who wants to do everything in his power
to capture, listen carefully to what I'm
about to say, to capture your mind.
Yes. How does he do it?
Does he do it all at once?
No, he doesn't do it all at once, does
he? He does it what?
Little by little. He does it slowly. He
does it over weeks and months and years.
And what happens is he will come and he
will capture a part of your mind and
bring it where
he'll bring it to Babylon.
Wait, I don't know if you
understood what I just said just now.
[snorts]
He will capture a little of your mind.
See, when you keep exercising that proud
look, that that gives Satan access to
your mind.
And when he has access to your mind, he
takes that part and he brings a little
piece of you into Babylon to his house.
And as you continue to allow Satan to
have access to your what everyone to
your mind, what happens is he takes a
little bit of you into Babylon. a little
bit of you into Babylon until we get to
the place where we begin to think
like Babylon.
I want you to understand this is what
God this is what Satan's trying to lead
you to. He wants you to be captured by
he wants your thinking process to be
Babylonian.
If I can get you
to begin to exercise proud looks,
lying tongues, the more I can get you to
do this is the more I'm bringing you
into captivity. Is the more I'm bringing
you into my dominion is the more I'm
bringing you under my power.
And so as we look at this Old Testament
sanctuary and how it was broken down
little by little and ultimately taken to
Babylon, what we're seeing here is a
picture of how Satan is seeking to
destroy each and every soul.
A proud look. Proverbs 16:18 says this,
"Pride goes before destruction and a
hardy spirit before a what? before a
fall.
Beloved, if we allow a proud look to
dominate us in the year 2020, guess
what?
You're not going to have a good
Christian year. How many of you would
like to have a good Christian year?
One of the first things you're going to
have to do, one of the first thing we
all have to do is learn how to conquer
that proud look, is learn how to
exercise humility over pride.
What about the labor? Remember how the
labor pointed to the the washing away of
sins?
Why does God wash away our sins the way
he does? What is what what do we call
that when God washes away our sins?
He cleanses us. Meaning he is doing
something. Why do we need the washing
away of sins? How do we get the washing
away of sins? What do we ask for?
We're asking to be
forgiven.
Forgiven.
How many of you are glad that God
forgives us?
And and then doesn't he say that because
he has forgiven us, [snorts]
he requires that we forgive others.
Yeah. But what is the reason that we
typically don't forgive others?
Pride is one.
How about bitterness?
You know what Hebrews 12 says about
bitterness? Let me read. Let's get it up
on the screen. Hebrews 12:14 and 15. The
Bible says, "Follow peace with all men
and holiness without which no man shall
see God, looking diligently, lest any uh
lest any root of what? bitterness spring
up and trouble you and thereby
many be what? Defile. If the purpose of
the labor is to cleanse, watch this
guys. Bitterness defiles.
And do you realize that as long as you
have a bitter root in your heart, you
are giving Satan access to work in you
and to slowly bring you into Babylon.
Who have you not forgiven?
Who do you refuse to give to forgive?
Who are you struggling with with
bitterness in your heart right now for?
Because bitterness is a door through
which the king of Babylon, Satan, can
have access to your temple.
What about this one?
The table of showbread.
table of showbre points us to the word
of God.
What is one of the easiest ways Satan
can have access to you because of the
word of God?
Someone said disobedience.
How about unbelief?
If God calls us to believe in his word,
can we exercise a spirit of unbelief
that will give Satan access to the
temple?
Notice again with me
[clears throat] Hebrews chapter 3:12,
the Bible says, "Take heed, brethren,
lest there be any of you uh having an
evil heart of what?" Unbelief in
departing from the living God.
God says he loves you. How many of you
believe that?
How many of you struggle to believe
that? Don't raise your hand.
Can you exercise unbelief in the love of
God for you?
Do you think Satan's a master of putting
doubt in the hearts of people? You're
not really important. God really doesn't
care about you. You're no one. No one
likes you. No one Do you think Satan
messes with people in that way?
Beloved, God is trying to tell us,
listen, don't believe the devil's lie.
Because if you have unbelief in your
heart, if you don't believe that I truly
love you, you are giving Satan access to
your heart to totally take your mind
away to where? To Babylon.
The altar of incense symbolize prayer.
Let me ask you, can lack of prayer lead
you to be taken captive by Babylon?
The the seven the seven branch
candlestick
represented light. I'm going to ask you
a question. Can dwelling in darkness?
Can dwelling on? How many of you like
don't raise your hand when something is
presented to you? You always see the
dark side. Don't raise your hand.
Can being pessimistic
cause Satan to have access to your mind?
Can you be pessimistic to the point
where no matter what someone does, you
know they were up to evil?
Like a person just cannot do good
because sometimes we call that like
street smarts. I know I can read people.
No, you can't read people.
Right. Only God can ultimately read the
heart. Amen.
Even the ark of the covenant, the ark of
the covenant pointed to to to to God's
to to the law of God which was
summarized by one word which is love.
Let me ask you a question. Can a
loveless heart be can Satan have access
to a loveless heart?
You see, beloved, listen. These are the
things that have either allowed Satan to
have access to so many of us that were
practically living in Babylon even
though we're in the church.
And God is saying, listen, if you want
to, if you want to stop it, there's a
way you can make a change.
You can actually change the way that you
do things.
You can go into 2020 no longer being
bound by by the lying tongue, being
bound by by feet or swift mist or hands
that shed innocent. You can you can
change things. You can become
a better Christian for 2020.
I want you to check this out.
Because how many of you remember how
Babylon how um Israel was ultimately
delivered from Babylon?
How was Israel
Who?
Say again. I thought I heard someone say
a name.
Cyrus.
Okay. Cyrus is the leader of the Meo
Persian Empire who God rose up to do
what? To deliver Israel. And I want you
to notice Isaiah 45. Isaiah chapter
45:1. Listen to what the Bible says
here. Thus say the Lord to his anointed
to Cyrus whose right hand I have holden
to subdue nations before him. I will
loose the loins of kings to open before
him the two leaved gates and the gate
shall not be shut. Now pause for a
second. What is this talking about?
What was s What are the two leaved gates
that Cyrus was going to open?
The gates of what kingdom?
Babylon.
God called Cyrus on the scene and and
and and set of Cyrus that he would, By
the way, Cyrus is called the anointed
one. Does that title sound familiar?
Does that title sound familiar? Cyrus,
beloved, was a type of who? Jesus. And I
want you to notice what it was said of
Cyrus. He would open the gates of
Babylon, but not only would he open the
gates of Babylon, notice with me Isaiah
44.
44 26 or verse 28. Isaiah 44:28.
The Bible says that saith of Cyrus, he
is my shepherd and shall perform all my
pleasure, even saying to Jerusalem, thou
shalt be built, and to the temple thy
foundation shall be laid. Okay, two
things Cyrus was supposed to do. He was
going to open the gates of Babylon to
set the captives free. And he was going
to tell the captives to go back to
Jerusalem and rebuild what? The temple.
Do you see a type of the work of Jesus
here?
Watch this guys.
Because of our own sins, because of our
own abominations being exercised in the
temple, we were taken captive. Some of
us are taken captive in Babylonian
thinking right now. I don't like you.
I have an issue with this. I have I am I
am I am I don't believe that God really
loves me. Our thinking has become
Babylonian.
But God does not leave us in captivity.
Jesus Christ says, "Listen, if you allow
me to, I will come into you. I will open
the gates that currently hold you
captive and set you free so that you can
go back and begin the work of
rebuilding.
How many of you would like a rebuilt
temple in 2020?
I want you to think about that. Many of
us have had our temples just totally
like ransacked
by Satan in 2019.
We are walking around with bitterness.
We're walking around with unbelief.
We're walking around with with anger.
We're walking around with all kinds of
stuff. The temple has been ransacked.
Jesus says, "If you let me, I will set
you free so that you can begin the work
of reformation."
I want you to understand something. When
Cyrus set the captives free, who how
many of you remember who it was that led
the reformation
to rebuild the temple?
Who was it?
It was not Nehemiah.
It was Ezra.
It was Ezra. And if you check out the
story of Ezra uh in in in Ezra chapter
1, you will notice that when Ezra begins
his reformation, the first thing that he
rebuilds, how many of you know what is
the first thing Ezra rebuilds to begin
the reformation of the temple?
It was the altar of sacrifice.
Beloved, please of
you want to begin the work of
reformation,
it begin it begin
with the spirit of humility. The spirit
of what everyone? humility
because without the spirit of humility,
nothing else is going to be
accomplished.
Without the spirit of humility, all else
fails.
So God is saying, listen, if you want to
rebuild the temple, the first thing that
must happen is you must let me into your
heart. I will open the gates and set you
free, and you are going to go and you're
going to begin the work of rebuilding
the temple. And the first thing I want
you to focus on is the spirit of
humility.
Humble yourself [snorts] in the sight of
the Lord and he will do what?
He will lift you up.
Now, did Ezra have a easy easy time
rebuilding the temple?
Was there opposition when it came to
Ezra building the temple? So you can
expect that as you're going about
seeking to rebuild humility,
seeking to exercise
forgiveness,
seeking to exercise truth instead of
unbelief.
When you go about doing these things,
are you going to run into
resistance?
Absolutely.
But beloved, if you are faithful, God
will complete the work in us. Amen.
So
Ezra begins the work of building the
temple.
What is he trying to do here?
What does it mean to rebuild a temple?
Asking for you and me now. What does it
mean for you and I to rebuild our
temples?
It's very simple, guys. To rebuild a
temple means to change
your mind.
It means to do what, everyone?
Change your mind. What do I mean, change
your mind?
Remember, it's the mind that controls
the hands, the feet. It's the mind that
controls the tongue. God says, "Listen,
in order for you not to end up in the
same place you were, in order for your
temple not to be ransacked, you need to
learn how to change your mind."
And we know that it is God that does it
in us and through us. But I want you to
listen very carefully because to change
your mind means something very literal.
It means I have to start thinking daily
about the principle of humility. Lord,
help me to be humble.
I need to exercise daily the principle
of forgiveness at the labor. Lord, help
me to learn how to forgive. You remember
we talked about neuroplasticity a few
weeks back.
Yes.
How when you learn how to think
something and you think it continually,
it begins to form new pathways in your
mind and it literally changes your mind.
God is trying to tell us, listen, if you
think through the articles of furniture
in the sanctuary, and if you do this
daily, it will change your
mind.
Amen.
So now I'm going to begin to ask, Lord,
give me opportunities to be humble.
Every day I'm going to get up and I want
to say, Lord, write humility in my mind.
Give me opportunities to forgive. Lord,
write forgiveness in my mind. Give me
opportunities to believe. Lord, write
belief in my mind. Write prayer in my
mind. Write letting my light shine in my
mind. Write loving your neighbor, loving
my neighbor in my mind. Write it in my
mind. So that I my mind is literally
being
changed.
You see, it was not enough for Ezra to
begin the reformation. He did not
complete the reformation. did he? It was
Nehemiah that came along afterward and
completed the reformation.
It's not enough for us to say, "Ah, it's
a new year and I'm going to change
things." And not follow it through.
Amen.
The Reformation has to be completed. And
so, let's talk about Nehemiah just for a
few moments before we close up. You see,
Nehemiah's work was to do something very
specific. How many of you know what that
was? It was to build what? Build a wall.
Why was a wall necessary?
What does a wall do?
It protects.
Listen carefully, beloved. The wall was
built to protect the temple.
It's not enough to just say, "I'm going
to change." A reformation must be
complete. In other words, you must learn
how to guard
your mind.
Not only must I begin to change my mind,
but Lord, help me to guard my mind so
that the enemy cannot have access to it
any longer.
Beloved, I don't know about you,
but I hate it
when I know that the enemy is messing
with my thinking.
when he's messing with me about what
this person did to you or what happened
here or what happened there and and and
the the possibilities of bitterness are
right there waiting for you to just
reach out and grab it. Yep, I'm bitter.
Yep, I'm angry. Yep, I'm I'm doubtful
right now. Yep, I don't believe. All
those things Satan is trying to to put
into your mind so that he can take you
captive. But God says, "Listen, I came
to set the captives
free."
So, beloved, what should your New Year's
resolution be? Among all the other
resolutions, this is what I believe our
New Year's resolution should be. Lord,
change my mind.
Change my mind.
Help me to begin thinking along these
principles. And not just weekly, not
just monthly. Help me to think these
principles daily.
Because if I think them daily, it's
going to have an effect on my mind and
my my my my temple, my sanctuary will be
cleansed. Satan will not have access to
take me captive as he does at his will.
So, it's 2020
and today you're saying, "All right,
Lord. It's time for a new temple.
Cuz this one has been just trampled upon
by the enemy.
Teach me
how to forgive.
how to love.
Teach me
how to humble myself.
Teach me.
Let me tell you it the way the Lord
teaches.
You want to be humble. You want to How
many of you would like to be humble?
God will bring you before people who you
are like I Lord I refuse to humble
myself before that person. And the
Lord's like well I thought you
thought you wanted to learn humility.
Lord teach me to love. How many of you
want to love love better? Oh amen. And
he'll bring you just that person that
you're like, "No, but not her, Lord. I
wasn't talking about her.
Teach me how to love someone. Yes, I can
love him. Teach me how to love him.
Teach me how to love that one, but not
her."
The Lord will bring the very people
before your path to teach you the very
lessons he needs. He needs to teach you.
You want a cleansed temple,
you have to trust the Lord.
You have to trust the Lord.
So my appeal today, come down to the
front if you're ready. You're saying
today, Lord, 2020, I need a new heart. I
need a new mind. I need a new temple.
[music]
I'm going to invite you to come down
because we're going to have a special
prayer prayer. Lord, I need a new
temple. [music]
My temple's been beat up.
It's time to start a new
It's time to start a new. [music]
The question is, do you surrender all?
Will you allow bitterness to dwell in
your heart?
You know what a lying tongue says? A
lying tongue says, "I don't have
bitterness bitterness in my heart." No.
A lying tongue denies
the reality of the condition of your
temple.
Don't deny the condition of your temple.
Begin there.
Help me Lord. Help me Lord.